Sol Biderman Collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Sol Biderman Collection 1958-2003
AFC 2006/019
Biderman, Sol
approximately 1741 items
approximately 1314 pages
326 chapbooks
3 sound tape reels: analog, 7 1⁄2 ips, mono.; 3 in.
70 wood block prints: black and white; various sizes
1 photographic print: black and white; 7 x 9 in.
6 posters: color, black and white; various sizes
3 postcards: color; various sizes
14 crucifixes
4 wooden boxes
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Brazilian chapbooks, xilogravuras woodblock illustrations and woodblocks, sound recordings and additional research material on the subject of Brazilian literatura de cordel collected by Sol Biderman. The collection also includes a play, poems, and other writings by Biderman along with his collection of Chicano corridos and poems.
Provenance
Sol Biderman; Purchase; 2006.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Materials
Brazilian woodcut prints collection (AFC 1999/033)
http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655396
David A. Taylor collection of literatura de cordel (AFC 2008/001)
http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655372
José Neistein collection of woodcuts and chapbooks from Brazil (AFC 2011/068)
http://lccn.loc.gov/2014655220
Henrique Vieira Leite collection of Brazilian literatura de cordel (AFC 2007/025)
http://lccn.loc.gov/2008700391
Literatura de cordel Brazilian chapbook collection, 1930-2015 (AFC 1970/002)
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006700204
Mary C. Karasch collection of literatura de cordel, 1975-2007 (AFC 2011/023)
http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655394
Some religious topoi in Anglo-American and Luso-Brazilian folk literature, 1977 / Sol Biderman (AFC 1977/042)
http://lccn.loc.gov/2009655427
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access to recordings and some fragile materials may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
A database containing bibliographic information for the chapbooks in the collection is also available by contacting the Folklife Reading Room.
Biographical Note
Born in Dallas, Texas in 1936, Sol Biderman has taught literature at universities in California; Genoa and Naples, Italy; and São Paulo, Brazil. He is the author of Bring Me to the Banqueting House and the plays When Elvis Met Che in Denver, To Kill a Mandarin, and Unabomber Hotel.
Biderman's interest in the cordel tradition dates to his tenure at the Faculdade de Filosofia de Marilia in São Paulo, Brazil in the 1960s, when he first began to collect chapbooks and meet the cordelistas who wrote them. In 1970, he donated a substantial portion of his chapbook collection to the Library of Congress (AFC 1970/002), which has continued to acquire literatura de cordel through the Library of Congress Office in Rio.
Scope and Content
The Sol Biderman Collection is comprised of Biderman's writings, research materials, and primary sources for his studies of folk literature including 326 Brazilian chapbooks published between 1958 and 2003, with related materials from other countries, including Mexico and Italy.
The collection includes material on performance, narratives, and Brazilian chapbook illustrating traditions. Three sound recordings, some of which were taped in Pernambuco, Rio Grande do Norte, and Ceara in 1967-1968, capture the recitation of the cordel poems "Beira Mar" and "Galope a Beira Mar." Artifacts and xilogravuras in the collection include a selection of wooden boxes by Guilherme de Faria (a.k.a. Alma Welt); a series of fourteen woodblocks depicting the crucifixion of Christ by João Antonio de Barros; woodblock prints from the Via Sacra series by José Costa Leite; and selected photographs from Inocêncio da Costa Niquel's (Mestre Noza) woodblock Via Sacra series, plus other woodblock prints and posters advertising Biderman's plays. Chapbook authors include: João Martins de Athayde, Abraão Batista, J. (José) Borges, Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante, Guilherme de Faria, Raimundo Santa Helena, Franklin de C. Machado, José Pacheco, Apolônio Alves dos Santos, and Minelvino Francisco Silva, among others.
Biderman's writings, including a play, poems, and articles form part of the Manuscripts series in the collection. Included are a selection of Chicano corridos and poems written by members of the Teatro Campesino and students of the Universidad Autonomia de Mexico in 1970-1972. Student poems were collected during the time Sol Biderman taught Chicano and English Literature at San Jose State University.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by format into the following series: Series 1: Manuscripts; Series 2: Sound Recordings; Series 3: Graphic Materials; Series 4: Artifacts. The chapbooks, graphic images, and artifacts have been arranged by author/creator last name and have been assigned unique numbers. Chapbooks originally housed in wooden boxes crafted by Guilherme de Faria were later added to the end of the chapbook range that was already alphabetized (EP001 to EP283), and can be found in Boxes 6-7 (EP284 to EP326). For an inventory of chapbooks, please see Appendix A. Published materials donated with the collection have been transferred to the Library of Congress General Collections.
Series 1: Manuscripts
Series 2: Sound Recordings
Series 3: Graphic Materials
Series 4: Artifacts.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Barros, João Antonio de, 1935-; Biderman, Sol; Faria, Guilherme de; Leite, José Costa; Niquel, Inocêncio da Costa, 1897-
Subjects
American poetry--20th century.; Brazilian poetry--Brazil--20th century.; Chapbooks, Brazilian--Brazil.; Corridos--Mexico.; Crucifixion in art.; Field recordings--Brazil.; Folk literature, Brazilian--Brazil--History and criticism.; Folk poetry, Brazilian.; Popular literature--Brazil--History and criticism.; Wood-engraving--Brazil.
Form/Genre
Chapbooks.; Field recordings.; Literatura de cordel.; Manuscripts.; Poems.; Sound recordings.; Wood blocks (printing blocks).; Woodcuts.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Finding aid., 22 pages. (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Donor correspondence. Email correspondence providing background information on the sound recordings and Chicano poems in the collection., 5 pages. (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Labeled envelopes: Photocopies. Photocopies of envelopes used to ship collection materials to the Library of Congress., 25 pages. (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Chapbook-related material: "O Cangaço na Cultura e na Realidade Brasileira" Universidade de São Paulo course syllabus and bibliography, 1966., 30 pages. (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Chapbook-related material: "Verdedeira Historia de Imperatriz Porcina" Photocopy of chapbook tale. 31 pages. (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Chapbook-related material: "Casamento Infeliz;" "D. Inez de Castro;" "Prefeis de Bandarra;" and "Prefeis de Beato" Photocopies of chapbook tales., 74 pages. (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Chicano/Mexican-related material: Poems Poems collected in 1970-1972 from members of Teatro Campesino and students of the Universidad Autonomia de Mexico., 22 pages. (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Chicano/Mexican-related material: El Corrido Mexicano (excerpts) Photocopied excerpts from the book edited by Vicente T. Mendoza., 70 pages. (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Chicano/Mexican-related material: El Corrido Mexicano (excerpts) Photocopied excerpts from another book of corridos., 61 pages. (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Published/bound materials: Chapbook covers (EP001-EP326) Photocopies of covers of chapbooks in Boxes 3-7., 168 pages. (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Published/bound materials: Primeira Coletãnea de Cordel; Morte e Vida Severina; and O Chamado de Deus na Terra Pela Sagrada Eucaristia. Collection of five chapbooks by João Antonio de Barros; The Death and Life of Severina by João Cabral de Melo Neto; and The Call of God in the Land of Christ by Francisco de Andrade., 242 pages. (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Published/bound materials: Dicionário de Flores, Folhas e Frutas and Tradições Paulistas Congadas. A dictionary of flowers, leaves, and fruits, no author, Livraria Teixeira, São Paulo, no date. A history of the Congadas festival honoring Saint Benedict, no author, Divisão de Turismo e Diversões Públicas, São Paulo, 1944., 49 pages. (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Inventory separation list: photocopies of items sent to the Library of Congress' General Collections List of books and photocopies of book covers., 98 pages. (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Writings: The Beatification of Carmen Miranda Play written by Sol Biderman, typescript., 42 pages. (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Writings: Catálogo de Literatura de Cordel Catalog of chapbooks held at the Faculdade de Filosofia, Ciências e Letras de Marília and at the Library of Congress by Sol Biderman, unpublished typescript, 1970., 79 pages. (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Writings: O Messias e o Fim do Mundo na Literatura de Cordel Christ and the End of the World in Cordel Literature by Sol Biderman, unpublished typescript, 1979., 121 pages. (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Writings: What Shall I Do In Summer? and other poems Signed book of poems by Sol Biderman, self published, Rio de Janeiro, 1961., 39 pages. (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Writings: Contos da Alma Songs of Alma by Alma Welt (pseudonym of Guilherme de Faria). One copy each of the unpublished and published manuscript, Editora Palavras e Gestos, São Paulo, 2004., 175 pages. (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Sound Recordings. Information on sound recordings in the collection., 1 page. (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Artifacts. Information on artifacts in the collection., 7 pages. (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Chapbooks EP001 – EP080. (Box 3)
  - Chapbooks EP081 – EP160. (Box 4)
  - Chapbooks EP161 – EP240. (Box 5)
  - Chapbooks EP241 – EP300. (Box 6)
  - Chapbooks EP301 – EP326. (Box 7)
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  Three sound recordings are original reel-to-reel 3-inch tapes; mono. double track; 7 1⁄2 ips. The tapes of Brazilian Literatura de cordel e cantadores nordestinos were recorded in Pernambuco, Rio Grande do Norte, and Ceara, in 1967-1968. They capture the recitation of the cordel ballad rhythms "Beira Mar" and "Galope a Beira Mar" etc., and other rhythms no longer sung. Sung by Joaquim Batista de Sena, Jose Mota, Manuel Morais, Natal; Jose João dos Santos (who went by the pseudonym of Azulao), Rio; and Francisco Genuíno (Natal).
  - Side A (12 minutes) (Item-id AFC 2006/019: SR01)
    Selections:
    1. Italian by unidentified person (probably a poem)
    2. Dante Aleghiere's Vita Nova, recited by a man in Italian
    3. Song sung in Spanish by a woman
  - Side B (12.5 minutes)
    All in Italian by the same man from 1A.
    1. Italian [poem; no title]
    2. Portame il girasole
    3. [no title]
    4. Languila
    5. Falsetto
    6. Da Mediterraneo
    7. Giuseppe Ungarette's Tutto ó Per tutto
    8. Matino
    9. Nongridate Piu
    10. Pasararondile
    11. Francesco Petrarca [author] [no title]
    12. [no title]
  - Side A (6 minutes) (Item-id AFC 2006/019: SR02)
    All in Portuguese
    1. Short ballad [no title] by 2 men, probably João Firmino and Joāo Adriano
    2. Galope à Beira Mar; João Firmino and Joāo Adriano, singers
    3. Quadrăo na Beira Mar
  - Side B (6 minutes)
    1. Lyrics by Priest Geraldo
    2. Singers [names unknown] sing music
    3. Religious music: 3 parts of a Catholic mass
    1) Entrance of the Priest / Beginning of Mass
    2) Ofertōrio – Offertory
    3) Comunhão – Communion
  - Side A (12 minutes) (Item-id AFC 2006/019: SR03)
    State: Ceará (Fortaleza)
    Singers: João Firmino and Adriano
    I. [No title]
    II. Quadrão
    III. Quadrão da Beira Mar
  - Side B 12 minutes)
    Martelo Agalopado (Decassílabo)
    Singers: Adriano and Firmino
    I. Martelo Agalopado (Decassílabo)
    II. Galope na Beira do Mar
- Series 3: Graphic Materials
  - Woodblock prints by Jota Barros, AFC 2006/019: GR01; Original print, black and white, 8 1⁄2 x 12 1⁄4 in., signed 1982; AFC 2006/019: GR02 (copy); Photocopy of Jota Barros image. See OS01 for original print. (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Woodblock prints by Guilherme de Faria, AFC 2006/019: GR03-GR20; Original prints, black and white, 8 1⁄2 x 12 1⁄4 in. (Box-folder 8/22)
  - Woodblock prints by Guilherme de Faria, AFC 2006/019: GR20 (copy 2) - GR37; Original prints, black and white, 8 1⁄2 x 12 1⁄4-in.; AFC 2006/019: GR38 (copy); Cover of a chapbook authored by Guilherme de Faria. See OS01 for original drawing. (Box-folder 8/23)
  - Woodblock prints by José Costa Leite, AFC 2006/019: GR39-GR53; Complete set of original prints from the illustrator's Via Sacra series, black and white, 6 x 8 1⁄2 in. (Box-folder 8/24)
  - Woodblock prints by Mestre Noza (Niquel, Inocêncio da Costa, 1897-1983), AFC 2006/019: GR54-GR63; Selected images from the illustrator's Via Sacra series. 10 photographic print images, black and white, 7 x 9 1⁄2 in. (Box-folder 8/25)
  - Woodblock prints, anonymous, AFC 2006/019: GR64-GR68 and AFC 2006/019: PH01; 6 photographic print images, black and white, 7 x 9 in.; AFC 2006/019: GR69-GR70; 2 back-to-back print images (Box-folder 8/26)
  - Postcards., AFC 2006/019: GR71-GR73; 3 blank picture postcards (Box-folder 8/27)
  - Print by Jota Barros, AFC 2006/019: GR02; 1 16 1⁄4 x 20 in. black-and-white woodblock print (Folder OS01)
  - Cover from chapbook authored by Guilherme de Faria, AFC 2006/019: GR38; 1 20 x 28 in. color drawing (Folder OS01)
  - Bring Me to the Banqueting House, AFC 2006/019: GR74; 1 8 1⁄2 x 11 1⁄2 in. black-and-white poster (Folder OS01)
  - When Elvis Met Che, AFC 2006/019: GR75; 1 11 3⁄4 x 16 1⁄2 in. black-and-white poster (Folder OS01)
  - To Kill a Mandarin, AFC 2006/019: GR76; 1 11 1⁄2 x 16 1⁄2 in. color poster (Folder OS01)
  - Beatification of Carman Miranda, AFC 2006/019: GR77; 1 11 1⁄2 x 16 1⁄2 in. color poster (Folder OS01)
  - Beatification of Carman Miranda: Carmen Pulls it Off, AFC 2006/019: GR78; 1 11 x 17 in. color poster (Folder OS01)
- Series 4: Artifacts
  - Woodblocks carved by Jota Barros, from the series on the crucifixion of Christ, AFC 2006/019: AR1 – AR14; 14 woodblocks, 4 1⁄2 x 5 1⁄4 x 1⁄4 in. (Box 9)
  - Handmade wooden boxes by Guilherme de Faria, AFC 2006/019: AR15 – AR18; 4 handmade wooden box containers, 8 x 6 x 3 1⁄4 in. (Box 9)
Appendix A: Inventory of Chapbooks
Indexed by the last name of the first author of the chapbook. The EP number is the location of the chapbook in the collection containers.
001 Alencar, Antônio Sena, 1928- A carta que chegou ao céu. Como foi remetida e a resposta vinda do céu.
002 Alencar, Antônio Sena, 1928- História da Cecília A Jovem Morta/Viva.
078 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- A Volta de Lampião ao Inferno.
080 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Encontro do Presidente Tancredo com o Presidente Getúlio Vargas no Céu.
081 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Jesus Cristo e o mestre dos Mestres.
082 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- O Amor que venceu a Morte.
083 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- O mofino que virou valente.
084 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- O sacrificio do amor ou o noivo ressussitado.
085 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Os Cabras de Lampião.
086 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Os Conselhos do Destino.
087 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Os Dois Amigo Leais.
088 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Os três Conselhos da Sorte.
089 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Peleja de Zé do Caixão com o Diabo.
090 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Rufino, O Rei do Barulho.
091 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- Zé Baiano, Vida e Morte.
092 Almeida Filho, Manoel d', 1914- De cangaceiro a Santo.
003 Almofala, Raimundo Ferreira de. Peleja de Raimundo Ferreira de Almofala com Mariano José da Silva / Cego Mariano.
004 Amaral, Firmino Teixeira do. Peleja ao Cego Aderaldo com Zé Pretinho.
005 Amaral, Firmino Teixeira do. Peleja do Cego Aderaldo com Zé Pretinho do Tucum.
006 Amorim, Siqueira de. O Reino do Catimbó e o Caboclo Mamador.
007 Arêda, Francisco Sales de. A pobresa em reboliço e os paus de arara do norte.
008 Arêda, Francisco Sales de. O Negrão do Paraná e o Seringueiro do Norte.
009 Athayde, Heitor. Historia de Barba Azul / Heitor Martins de Athayde.
010 Athayde, João Martins de. A Batalha de Oliveiros com Ferrabraz.
011 Athayde, João Martins de. A Prisão de Oliveiros.
012 Athayde, João Martins de. Discrição do Beijo.
013 Athayde, João Martins de. Entre o Amor e a Espada.
014 Athayde, João Martins de. História da Donzela Teodora.
015 Athayde, João Martins de. História do Capitão do Navio.
016 Azevedo, Téofilo de. A Vida de Guimãres Rosa.
017 Azevedo, Téofilo de. Zé Côco do Riachão.
018 Barros, Homero do Rêgo. O Carnaval de Pernambuco.
019 Barros, Homero do Rêgo. Visita do Santo Papa ao Recife.
020 Barros, João Antonio de, 1935- Lampião e Maria Bonita no Paraíso. Tentados por Satanás / Jotabarros.
021 Barros, João Antonio de, 1935- Peleja de Guaiatã de Coqueiro com Sebasto do Rio Grande / Jotabarros.
022 Barros, Leandro Gomes de, 1865-1918. A Batalha de Oliveiros com Ferrabrás, A Prisão de Oliveiros.
023 Barros, Leandro Gomes de, 1865-1918. Estória do Reino da Pedra Fina, Moizaniel e Angeltrina.
024 Barros, Leandro Gomes de, 1865-1918 História da Donzela Teodora.
025 Barros, Leandro Gomes de, 1865-1918. Juvenal e o Dragão.
026 Barros, Leandro Gomes de, 1865-1918. Os Martírios de Genoveva.
027 Barros, Leandro Gomes de, 1865-1918. Os Sofrimentos de Alzira.
028 Batista, Abraão. A morte de Padre Silvino e o significado da fé, ou do amor.
029 Batista, Abraão. A Vingança do diabo. depois da Apresentação de Chacrinha no Inferno.
030 Batista, Abraão. As Profecias do Padre Cícero.
031 Batista, Abraão. As Professias Sobre o Papa e o fim do Mundo.
032 Batista, Abraão. Nascimento, Vida e Morte de uma Coroa.
033 Batista, Abraão. Uma apresentação de Chacrinha no inferno.
034 Boccaccio, Giovanni, 1313-1375. A Mulher que queria ser Égua.
035 Borges, J. (José), 1935- A chegada da prostituta no céu / J. Borges.
036 Borges, J. (José), 1935- A descrição dos cornos / J. Borges.
037 Borges, J. (José), 1935- A desventura de um corno ganancioso / J. Borges.
038 Borges, J. (José), 1935- A Moça que virou jumenta porque falou de topless com Frei Damião / J. Borges.
039 Borges, J. (José), 1935- Como evitar a Aids / J. Borges.
040 Borges, J. (José), 1935- Domiciano e Rosete ou O viajante da sorte / J. Borges.
041 Borges, J. (José), 1935- Exemplo do filho que matou os Pais para ficar com a aposentadoria / J. Borges.
042 Borges, J. (José), 1935- Nazaré e Damião, o triunfo do amor entre a vingança e a morte / J. Borges.
043 Borges, J. (José), 1935- O valor que o peido tem / J. Borges.
044 Borges, J. (José), 1935- Luiz, José. Dicionario da Amizade / J. Borges.
247 Borges, Severino. Peleja de Severino Borges com Patativa do Norte.
248 Borges, Severino. Peleja de Severino Borges com Patativa do Norte.
045 Brandão, Sátiro Xavier. A triste sorte de Jovelina.
046 Brandão, Sátiro Xavier. O exemplo da Mocidade.
229 Caboclo e Silva, Manoel, 1916- Jesus, São Pedro e o Ferreiro Rei dos Jogadores.
230 Caboclo e Silva, Manoel, 1916- O Casamento da Porca com Zé da Lasca.
231 Caboclo e Silva, Manoel, 1916- O Valente Cascavel do Sertão Alagoano.
232 Caboclo e Silva, Manoel, 1916- Manassés e Marilí Entre a Luta e o Amor.
047 Cabral, João Firmino, 1940- O Monstro sem Alma.
048 Câmara, Teodoro Ferraz da. História de Rosa de Milão.
050 Campos, Francisco de Souza. As Aventuas de Carlos e o Amor de Zulmirinha.
051 Caretta, Walter José. Um amor e dois destinos.
052 Carioca, Inacio. Romance de João Cambadinho e a Princesa do reino de Mira-Mar.
054 Carmo, Luiz Ferreira do. A Morte que abalou o mundo. O Assassinato do Presidente Kennedy.
055 Carvalho, Elias A. de. Folheto sobre o 1.o congresso dos poetas da lietratura de cordel.
056 Carvalho, João Gomes de. Na Marcha dos Tempos.
057 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. A Chegada de Lampião no Céu / Trovador B.
058 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. A crueldade dos donos de terras para com os pobres lavradores / Trovador B.
059 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. A Moça que Bateu na Mãe e Virou Cachorra / Trovador Brasileiro.
060 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. A Vida do Santo Papa João Paulo II / Trovador Brasileiro.
061 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. ABC da Minha Terra / Trovador Brasileiro.
062 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. Antonio Conselheiro O Santo Guerreiro de / Trovador Brasileiro.
063 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. Cuíca de Santo Amaro. O Poeta Popular que Conheci / Trovador Brasileiro.
064 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. Maceió do Tempo do Major Bonifácio / Trovador Brasileiro.
065 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. O Encontro de Rodolfo Cavalcante com Lampião Virgulino / Trovador Brasileiro.
066 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. O filho que Levantou Falso á Mãe e Virou Bicho / Trovador Brasileiro.
067 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. Os Canarinhos de Deus / Trovador Brasileiro.
068 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. Senhor Deus dos Exilados / Trovador Brasileiro.
069 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986. Tudo na Terra tem Fim / Trovador Brasileiro.
070 Cavalcante, Rodolfo Coelho, 1919-1986; Ramos, José Crispim. A Peleja de Rodolfo Cavalcante com Caboquinho da Bahia / Trovador Brasileiro.
072 Cavenaghi, Hélio, 1927-, ed. Festa da Bicharada.
073 Cavenaghi, Hélio, 1927-, ed. O Exemplo do Menino que Falou no Ventre da Mãe.
074 Cordeiro, José. Estória do Reino da Pedra Azul (Grande Romance de Luta e Amôr, Encantos e Mistérios).
075 Costa, Luiz da. História do Papagaio Misterioso e os Sofrimentos de Jobão.
076 Cristo Rei, João de, 1900-1983. Profecia de Frei Vidal da Penha para o ano 1966.
077 Cristo Rei, João de, 1900-1983. Um Sonho Misterioso de Padrinho Cícero Romão.
071 Dila, José Cavalcanti e Ferreira. Dila o Ex-Cangaceiro.
094 Evangelista, João Lucas. As Aventuras de João Desmantelado.
296 Faria, Guilherme de. Máximas do Trovador Sertanejo.
322 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Candiléia.
316 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Dívida Herdada.
297 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Doralice.
323 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Dupla Sertaneja ou "A Valsa de Mefisto".
298 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Encantada.
299 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Fauna da Cratera (Para as Crianças de Vargem Grande).
284 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Jaqueira Maldita.
285 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Justiça Seca.
300 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Noite de Guarda.
286 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Noiva Malfadada.
287 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Teia Cordel.
324 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Tocaia.
317 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Travessia.
288 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance da Vidência.
318 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance das Três Léguas.
301 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Alcoviteiro do Rei.
289 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Bambúrrio.
302 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Bobo da Aldeia.
303 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Cavalo de Pau.
304 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Cordelista.
319 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Coronel e a Donzela ou Conto de Fadas do Sertão.
305 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Cunhado Inesperado.
290 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Diabo da Borda da Mata.
306 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Laço de Amor Eterno.
307 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Leitâozinho.
291 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Narciso do Sertão.
308 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Padre Apaixonado.
292 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Palhaço.
293 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Rei da Grota.
309 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Retorno.
325 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Tuím ou "O Legado da Gerusa."
320 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance do Vaqueiro Rei.
310 Faria, Guilherme de. Romance dos Tipos do Sertão.
311 Faria, Guilherme de. Quadras e Quintas do Trovador Sertanejo.
312 Faria, Guilherme de. Sonetos da Sertaneja.
313 Faria, Guilherme de. Um Outro Pavão Misterioso.